Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have part 7 of our series all about giving a presentation
我是Catherine，今天是我们关于做演示系列的第7部分。
in English.
用英语进行演示。
That's right.
没错。
So obviously not every presentation is going to go perfectly.
显然，不是每个演示都会完美进行。
Sometimes we do have some problems and on this occasion we're going to take a look at
有时候我们确实会遇到一些问题，这次我们要看看
tech problems and how to handle them.
技术问题以及如何处理它们。
That's right.
没错。
So you're going to learn some great ways to discuss and to explain technical problems.
所以你会学到一些很好的方法来讨论和解释技术问题。
Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
我们来听听我们的对话。
Okay so if we could dim the lights Jonathan we can kick off with the first TV advert.
好的，如果我们能把灯光调暗一点，Jonathan，我们就可以开始播放第一个电视广告了。
Please note that we're still in the early days with this advert so it might seem a bit
请注意，这个广告还处于早期阶段，所以可能看起来有点
rough around the edges.
粗糙。
Okay so I just need to click this and the advert should pop up on the screen.
好的，我只需要点击这里，广告应该会出现在屏幕上。
Hmm.
嗯。
Sorry about this.
抱歉。
Bear with me a second.
请稍等一下。
There seems to be a problem with the projector.
投影仪似乎有问题。
Let me see.
让我看看。
Jonathan, could you lend a hand a second?
乔纳森，能搭把手吗？
It looks like the projector is not recognizing the computer.
看起来投影仪没识别到电脑。
Let me check the connection a second.
让我检查一下连接。
Well the connection seems okay and the computer is running normally.
嗯，连接看起来没问题，电脑也正常运行。
Hmm.
嗯。
Okay.
好吧。
Sorry guys.
抱歉各位。
Obviously a problem with the system.
显然是系统出了问题。
Let's just reboot and start over.
咱们重启一下重新开始吧。
Let's see if this resolves the issue.
看看这样能不能解决问题。
Right let's try again.
好，再试一次。
No still nothing Michael.
不行，还是没反应，迈克尔。
There might be a technical issue with the projector.
可能是投影仪有技术故障。
I think maybe the projector has overheated.
我觉得投影仪可能过热了。
We might need to cool it down for 10 minutes and start again.
我们可能需要让它冷却10分钟再重新开始。
I'll call IT support to come over right now.
我马上叫IT支持过来。
Okay guys.
好了各位。
Unfortunately technical problems do crop up from time to time don't they?
不幸的是，技术问题时不时就会冒出来，对吧？
But it's not a huge problem.
但这也不是什么大问题。
In the meantime while the IT guys get to work on that, I can talk a little bit more about
在IT人员处理这个问题的同时，我可以再多讲一点关于
the advertising concept and what we are looking to achieve overall with this campaign.
广告概念以及我们希望通过这次活动整体实现的目标。
Alright so we're back and now let's take a look at five keywords that we've picked out
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看我们挑选出的五个关键词。
for you on Language Takeaway.
在“语言小贴士”环节为你准备。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
Okay so we have some phrasal verbs today.
好的，今天我们有一些短语动词。
The first one is to kick off.
第一个是“kick off”。
That's right.
没错。
Mr. Ford started out by saying that we can kick off the first TV advert.
福特先生一开始就说我们可以启动第一个电视广告。
So this phrasal verb to kick off, what does it mean?
那么这个短语动词“kick off”是什么意思呢？
It means to start something.
它的意思是开始某件事。
So to kick it off means to start.
所以“kick it off”就是开始的意思。
So I can say tonight we're kicking off the party at 8 o'clock.
所以我可以说明晚我们8点开始派对。
That's right.
没错。
Or let's kick off this new product with a big party.
或者让我们用一场盛大的派对来启动这个新产品。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So the phrasal verb to kick off.
所以短语动词“kick off”。
You've probably also seen it in sports.
你可能也在体育中见过它。
I think in soccer you have the kickoff which is the same thing.
我想在足球里，有“kickoff”这个词，意思是一样的。
That's right except it's a noun.
没错，只不过它是名词形式。
So be careful with that one.
所以那个要小心一点。
The kickoff is the very beginning of the game.
开球就是比赛刚开始的时候。
Okay very good.
好的，非常好。
In that same paragraph towards the end, we see Mr. Ford saying okay so I just need to
在同一段落的末尾，我们看到福特先生说，好吧，我只需要
click this and the advert should pop up on the screen.
点击这个，广告就会在屏幕上弹出来。
Pop.
弹出。
Right.
对。
I like this verb actually because it makes me think of that.
我其实很喜欢这个动词，因为它让我想到那个场景。
That when you're using a computer and you have these little windows or these little
就是当你用电脑时，那些小窗口或小图标，
icons, those little pictures, when something changes, they appear quickly.
那些小图片，当有变化时，它们会快速出现。
And that means in computer talk, it means to pop up.
在电脑术语里，这就叫“弹出”。
That's right.
没错。
You obviously maybe heard of this already.
你显然可能已经听说过这个了。
You have annoying pop-ups.
你有烦人的弹窗广告。
Maybe you visit a website and all of a sudden these new windows start to open.
也许你访问一个网站，突然这些新窗口开始打开。
They're all advertisements.
它们全是广告。
You buy this, buy this, buy this, buy this.
买这个，买这个，买这个，买这个。
Those are pop-ups.
那些就是弹窗。
But also you can have a pop-up in a chat window for example.
但也可以有聊天窗口的弹窗，比如。
And in this case, we also use it as a verb.
在这种情况下，我们也把它用作动词。
It should pop up.
它应该会弹出来。
So to pop up.
所以“pop up”就是弹出来。
To appear.
出现。
All right very good.
好的，非常好。
Now obviously it didn't work.
现在显然它没起作用。
Something was happening with the projector and Mr. Ford was going through maybe some
投影仪出了点问题，福特先生正在检查可能的一些
of the problems and he said let me check the connection a second.
问题，他说让我检查一下连接。
Well the connection seems okay.
嗯，连接看起来没问题。
Okay connection is a very important noun especially when we're talking about technical things
好的，“connection”是一个非常重要的名词，尤其是当我们谈论技术性东西时，
like computers.
比如电脑。
You can have an internet connection.
你可以有网络连接。
This means how you are able to use the internet.
这意味着你能够使用互联网的方式。
But in this case we're talking about a projector which makes things bigger and a computer.
但在这个例子中，我们谈论的是投影仪（它能让东西变大）和电脑。
And so those things need to have a connection.
所以这些东西需要有一个连接。
They need to have a cord or something that you plug into one and to the other so that
它们需要一根线或什么东西，你把它插到一个设备上，再插到另一个设备上，这样
they can talk to each other.
它们就能互相通信。
That's right.
没错。
So as you notice, we are using it as a noun.
所以正如你注意到的，我们把它用作名词。
They need to have, the computer and the projector needs to have a connection.
它们需要有一个连接，电脑和投影仪需要有一个连接。
So you have the verb to connect but then you have the noun a connection.
所以你有动词“to connect”，然后有名词“a connection”。
All right and let's move on to another possible solution.
好的，我们继续看另一个可能的解决方案。
Mr. Ford suggests rebooting the system.
福特先生建议重启系统。
Okay so the verb here to reboot is another special computer word that means to turn off
好的，这里的动词“to reboot”是另一个特殊的电脑词汇，意思是关闭
and turn on again.
再重新打开。
To restart.
重新启动。
So if I say reboot, I'm using the prefix there re which means a repetition or to do it again.
所以如果我说“reboot”，我用了前缀“re”，表示重复或再做一次。
If I just say boot, can I say just I need to boot the computer?
如果我只说“boot”，我能说“我需要启动电脑”吗？
I need to boot up the computer.
我需要启动电脑。
Okay, boot up.
好的，启动。
That's right.
没错。
So in this case, you would be talking about a computer that is off and you want to turn
所以在这种情况下，你谈论的是一台关着的电脑，你想把它
it on.
打开。
So I would say, hey Marco, can you boot up the computer for me?
所以我会说，嘿，Marco，你能帮我启动电脑吗？
Now about using the word reboot or to boot up, it's usually for electronic things, electric
关于使用“reboot”或“boot up”这个词，通常用于电子设备、电器
things.
类的东西。
You wouldn't say to reboot your car or to boot up your car.
你不会说“重启你的车”或“启动你的车”。
No, this is for computers specifically electronics.
不，这特指电脑和电子产品。
For example, oh man, my iPhone just froze.
例如，哦，天哪，我的iPhone死机了。
I need to reboot it.
我需要重启它。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
All right and for our last phrasal verb for today on Language Takeaway, we have towards
好的，今天“语言小贴士”的最后一个短语动词，在
the end of the dialogue, towards the end of the dialogue, Mr. Ford apologizes and says,
对话的结尾，福特先生道歉说，
you know what, I'm sorry but technical problems do crop up sometimes.
你知道吗，很抱歉，但技术问题有时确实会突然出现。
Okay so this verb to crop up means to appear or to happen but not all the time.
好的，这个动词“to crop up”意思是出现或发生，但不是一直发生。
So unexpectedly or occasionally.
所以是意外地或偶尔地发生。
That's right.
没错。
So these things do crop up sometimes.
所以这些事情有时确实会突然出现。
It means every once in a while this problem will happen.
意思是每隔一段时间这个问题就会发生。
So can I use this for a person?
那我能用它来形容人吗？
If you say, oh you scared me, you cropped up on me.
如果你说，哦，你吓到我了，你突然出现在我面前。
No, it'd be creeped up on me.
不，那应该是“creeped up on me”（悄悄靠近我）。
Creeped up, very good.
“Creeped up”，非常好。
So we can't confuse those two but they sound very similar.
所以我们不能混淆这两个词，但它们听起来很像。
They do sound similar but to crop up is usually a problem or an event or a thing that happens
它们确实听起来很像，但“to crop up”通常指一个问题、一个事件或一件事发生，
and it happens not very often.
而且不经常发生。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So I think we've taken a look at a lot of words here, specifically phrasal verbs.
所以我想我们已经看了很多词，特别是短语动词。
So let's review those.
让我们回顾一下这些。
Let's listen to our dialogue again.
让我们再听一遍对话。
Okay so if we could dim the lights, Jonathan, we can kick off with the first TV advert.
好的，如果能把灯调暗一点，乔纳森，我们就可以开始播放第一个电视广告了。
Please note that we are still in the early days with this advert so it might seem a bit
请注意，这个广告还处于早期阶段，所以可能看起来有点
rough around the edges.
粗糙。
Okay so I just need to click this and the advert should pop up on the screen.
好的，我只需要点击这个，广告就应该会出现在屏幕上。
Hmm, sorry about this.
嗯，抱歉。
Bear with me a second.
请稍等一下。
There seems to be a problem with the projector.
投影仪似乎有问题。
Let me see.
让我看看。
Jonathan, could you lend a hand a second?
乔纳森，你能过来帮个忙吗？
It looks like the projector is not recognizing the computer.
看起来投影仪没有识别到电脑。
Let me check the connection a second.
让我检查一下连接。
Well the connection seems okay and the computer is running normally.
嗯，连接看起来没问题，电脑也正常运行。
Hmm.
嗯。
Okay, sorry guys.
好的，抱歉各位。
Obviously a problem with the system.
显然是系统出了问题。
Let's just reboot and start over.
我们重启一下，重新开始吧。
Let's see if this resolves the issue.
看看这样能不能解决问题。
Right, let's try again.
好的，再试一次。
No, still nothing, Michael.
不，还是没反应，迈克尔。
There might be a technical issue with the projector.
投影仪可能有个技术问题。
I think maybe the projector has overheated.
我觉得可能是投影仪过热了。
We might need to cool it down for 10 minutes and start again.
我们可能需要让它冷却10分钟，然后再重新开始。
I'll call IT support to come over right now.
我现在就叫IT支持过来。
Okay guys, unfortunately technical problems do crop up from time to time, don't they?
好了各位，不幸的是，技术问题时不时就会冒出来，对吧？
But it's not a huge problem.
但这也不是什么大问题。
In the meantime, while the IT guys get to work on that, I can talk a little bit more
与此同时，在IT人员处理这个问题的时候，我可以再多讲一点
about the advertising concept and what we are looking to achieve overall with this campaign.
关于广告概念以及我们这次活动想要达成的整体目标。
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at some phrases on Fluency Builder.
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看Fluency Builder上的一些短语。
Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder。
So this first phrase we have is very important, especially when we're using video or a projector
所以这第一个短语非常重要，尤其是当我们在演示中使用视频或投影仪时
in a presentation.
在演示中。
We say, let's dim the lights.
我们会说，让我们把灯光调暗。
That's right.
没错。
So we have the verb to dim.
所以我们有动词“调暗”。
So to dim something is to make it darker.
所以调暗某物就是让它变得更暗。
But not turn it off completely.
但不是完全关掉。
No.
不是。
It means maybe to lower the lights.
它意味着可能降低灯光亮度。
We could actually see this on a computer also when the screen is very, very bright.
我们在电脑上也能看到这种情况，当屏幕非常亮的时候。
We say, oh it's too bright.
我们会说，哦，太亮了。
I need you to dim it a little.
我需要你把它调暗一点。
Make it a little bit darker.
让它暗一点。
Okay.
好的。
So you can use this verb to dim to make it a little bit darker or to make it lower in
所以你可以用这个动词“调暗”来让它变暗一点或降低
intensity.
强度。
That's right.
没错。
Dim the color, dim the lights.
调暗颜色，调暗灯光。
Alright, very good.
好的，非常好。
Now Mr. Ford when he was talking about the advert, he said, well it's new and it's not
现在福特先生谈到广告时，他说，嗯，这是新的，而且还没有
ready yet completely.
完全准备好。
So it might seem a bit rough around the edges.
所以它可能看起来有点粗糙。
Okay.
好的。
This is a very, very popular phrase that means that something is incomplete.
这是一个非常非常流行的短语，意思是某物还不完整。
Maybe it's not perfect yet.
可能还不完美。
It needs some work.
还需要一些改进。
Okay.
好的。
So if maybe you're designing a new website and it's maybe 50% done.
所以如果你在设计一个新网站，可能完成了50%。
So you say the website is almost finished, but it's still rough around the edges.
你会说网站差不多完成了，但还是有点粗糙。
We need to make some changes to fix it.
我们需要做一些修改来完善它。
That's right.
没错。
Rough around the edges is a phrase that is the opposite of the word polished.
“粗糙”这个短语是“精致”的反义词。
Something is polished if it's perfect and ready to go.
如果某物是精致的，那就意味着它完美无缺，可以用了。
Okay.
好的。
And well, when the technical problem started, Mr. Ford was apologizing and said, hey, look,
嗯，当技术问题出现时，福特先生道歉说，嘿，听着，
I'm sorry.
对不起。
And he also used this interesting phrase, bear with me.
他还用了一个有趣的短语，“请耐心等待”。
Bear with me a second.
请稍等一下。
Okay.
好的。
So this is interesting because it's not the animal, the bear.
这很有趣，因为它不是指动物熊。
Right, right.
对，对。
This is different.
这是不同的。
It's more like, excuse me, please be patient.
它更像是，对不起，请耐心点。
I have to do something and you have to wait.
我得做点事，你得等一下。
So this is a very, very polite way of asking some people or some person to wait for you.
所以这是一种非常非常礼貌的方式，请求别人或某人等你。
To tolerate.
容忍。
Yes.
是的。
So both the animal bear and to bear with me are spelled the same way.
所以动物熊和“请耐心等待”的拼写是一样的。
It looks exactly like the animal, but we're not talking about the animal.
它看起来完全像动物，但我们不是在说动物。
No, we're asking someone to tolerate something that's annoying or frustrating.
不，我们是在请求某人容忍一些烦人或令人沮丧的事情。
Okay.
好的。
For example, I'm trying to show you a file on my computer, Marco.
例如，Marco，我正想给你看我电脑上的一个文件。
My computer's not working.
我的电脑不工作了。
I say, please bear with me a second.
我会说，请稍等一下。
I have to reboot my computer.
我得重启电脑。
I have to wait here.
我得在这儿等着。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
Now, towards the end of the dialogue, when we talked about to crop up, the second part
现在，在对话快结束时，当我们谈到“突然出现”时，第二部分
of that, Mr. Ford said, unfortunately, technical problems do crop up from time to time.
福特先生说，不幸的是，技术问题时不时就会冒出来。
So we already discussed cropped up.
我们已经讨论过“突然出现”了。
What is time to time?
“时不时”是什么意思？
From time to time.
时不时。
Okay.
好的。
So that's a set phrase because we said already that you could also say sometimes.
这是一个固定短语，因为我们已经说过你也可以说“有时”。
So from time to time means every once in a while or occasionally.
所以“时不时”意思是偶尔或间或。
So it's an adverbial phrase.
所以它是一个副词短语。
It's a way of telling people how often something happens, but in this case, it's not very common.
这是一种告诉人们某事发生频率的方式，但在这里，它不是很常见。
So for example, you can say, I like to go to the movies from time to time.
例如，你可以说，我时不时喜欢去看电影。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe once or twice a month, you like to go to the movies.
所以可能一个月一两次，你喜欢去看电影。
But what if I come to work every day?
但如果我每天都来上班呢？
Do I come to work from time to time?
我是不是偶尔来上班？
No.
不。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
So from time to time is rarely or occasionally, not very often.
所以“from time to time”意思是很少或偶尔，不经常。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好了。
Very good.
非常好。
So now let's listen to our dialogue one last time and review everything we've just learned.
那么现在我们最后听一遍对话，回顾一下我们刚学的内容。
Okay.
好的。
So if we could dim the lights, Jonathan, we can kick off with the first TV advert.
所以如果我们能把灯光调暗一点，乔纳森，我们就可以开始播放第一支电视广告了。
Please note that we're still in the early days with this advert, so it might seem a
请注意，这支广告还处于早期阶段，所以可能看起来有点
bit rough around the edges.
粗糙。
Okay.
好的。
So I just need to click this and the advert should pop up on the screen.
所以我只需要点一下这个，广告就会出现在屏幕上。
Hmm.
嗯。
Sorry about this.
抱歉。
Bear with me a second.
请稍等一下。
There seems to be a problem with the projector.
投影仪好像有问题。
Let me see.
让我看看。
Jonathan, could you lend a hand a second?
乔纳森，你能过来帮个忙吗？
It looks like the projector is not recognizing the computer.
看起来投影仪没有识别到电脑。
Let me check the connection a second.
让我检查一下连接。
Well, the connection seems okay and the computer is running normally.
嗯，连接看起来没问题，电脑也正常运行。
Hmm.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
Sorry, guys.
抱歉，各位。
Obviously a problem with the system.
显然是系统出了问题。
Let's just reboot and start over.
我们重启一下，重新开始吧。
Let's see if this resolves the issue.
看看这样能不能解决问题。
Right.
对。
Let's try again.
我们再试一次。
No, still nothing, Michael.
不，还是没反应，迈克尔。
There might be a technical issue with the projector.
投影仪可能有技术问题。
I think maybe the projector has overheated.
我想可能是投影仪过热了。
We might need to cool it down for 10 minutes and start again.
我们可能需要让它冷却10分钟，然后再重新开始。
I'll call IT support to come over right now.
我现在就叫IT支持过来。
Okay, guys.
好的，各位。
Unfortunately, technical problems do crop up from time to time, don't they?
不幸的是，技术问题时不时就会出现，对吧？
But it's not a huge problem.
但这不是什么大问题。
In the meantime, while the IT guys get to work on that, I can talk a little bit more
与此同时，当IT人员处理这个问题时，我可以再多讲一点
about the advertising concept and what we're looking to achieve overall with this campaign.
关于广告概念以及我们这次活动想要达到的整体目标。
All right.
好的。
So this was part seven of our presentation series.
这是我们演示系列的第七部分。
And actually, these type of problems occur very, very often, specifically with the laptop
实际上，这类问题非常非常常见，特别是笔记本电脑
and the projector.
和投影仪之间。
And sometimes it doesn't work.
有时候就是不行。
It doesn't recognize it.
它识别不了。
And so this is a nice way of handling it.
所以这是一个很好的处理方式。
This is.
就是这样。
And we hope that these are phrases that you can use in your daily life as well.
我们希望这些短语也能在你的日常生活中用到。
Maybe you're working with your colleagues and you're having some technical problems.
也许你和同事一起工作时遇到了一些技术问题。
Or if you're having a problem and someone gives you instructions for how to solve that
或者如果你遇到问题，有人给你指示如何解决那个
problem.
问题。
Like, I often get this from my technical team.
比如，我经常从我的技术团队那里听到这个。
I say, listen, I have a problem.
我说，听着，我有个问题。
And they say, hey, just reboot your computer and it will be okay.
他们就说，嘿，重启一下电脑就好了。
So these are very, very common issues that I think that you can learn how to describe
所以这些都是非常非常常见的问题，我认为你可以通过今天的课程学会如何用英语描述
in English with today's lesson.
它们。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And of course, if you guys have any questions or any doubts about this or any of our lessons,
当然，如果你们对这个或我们任何课程有任何问题或疑问，
please come to our website EnglishPod.com.
请访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
On the lessons page, you can leave your comments and questions.
在课程页面上，你可以留下评论和问题。
And we'll see you guys next time.
我们下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
영 studaos improve election sagas
嗯，学生改进选举传奇。